[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
tricentis TSA Advanced Training so this
is our lesson 14 as part of our TSA
Advanced Training or it's a lesson 29 as
an overall tric tasa
training so this is our part part three
of conditional statements and Loops as
you already know I've already published
two parts Part One covering if then L
statements part two covering do
statements and in this part I'm going to
cover how can we use while statements
while using or while automating your
test cases by using trient Taska please
do subscribe to to the channel click on
Bell icon you'll receive notifications
whenever I publish more
videos so while conditional statement so
first of all when you create while
statements tsco will automatically
create two objects one is Loop object
and the other one is condition object so
if the condition is
fulfilled test steps within the loop
object are run repeatedly until the
condition is no longer
fulfilled so while statements contain
the property called maximum repetitions
in order to avoid infinite
Loops that means because first it
searches for the condition it enters to
The Loop and the loop repeats until the
condition does not meet what if the
condition whatever you automated it does
not not meet forever then it's going to
go for the infinite Loops that's why you
can Define maximum
repetitions for any while Loops okay so
now let us see the order of conditions
so first while comes and then the
condition within the while statement
comes and then Loop within the while
statement comes okay so now let us jump
onto the system and see an example by
automating one test case or a scenario
and we will use the while statement
while you automating our test case so
this is my TSA latest version 16 okay so
before we start using while
statement while automating our test case
let me explain you what is the scenario
that we are going to automate so that I
can use while very effectively okay so
let's go go back to my web shop okay so
what we are going to do we are going to
automate empty shopping cart
scenario what it means so before I
execute any test case right I want to
make sure that your shopping cart is
empty okay so for that once you are into
shopping cart so if you see this is your
shopping cart table so at the back end
it's a web table where your all the
items will be stored okay so I need to
empty this shopping cart how check the
item if the shopping cart exist any item
check this click on update shopping cart
that will remove that item and
again I want to check do you have any
items yes I found one other item check
this click on update shopping cart so
now do I have any other item into
shopping cart yes check this and update
shopping cart do you have any other item
in the shopping cart no now I need to
exit I mean exit means I need to click
on log out wait until login appears and
then close the browser okay that's what
I need to automate that is the scenario
okay so let's go back to my trient tasar
so as I told you I need to create a new
workspace
and I need to
import the TSU file additional material
based TSU file so that I will have some
predefined libraries and predefined
modules that are already created so if
you want to access all these materials
like presentation PDF and then this um
TSU files you can basically go to my
udmi course you can subscribe to my udmi
course I'm going to leave my uh udmi
course in the description okay um where
you can access all the artifacts and and
also in fact you can simply access the
entire workspace that I'm working on
okay so now let's go here and create a
new
workspace okay so let's name this as
automation
specialist level two and I want to use a
workspace template here I don't want to
use a standard TSU I want to use this
one okay additional material based TSU
browse
this and then yeah this is the one okay
this is the one I want to use and then
open this now click on okay so now it is
going to create a new workspace where
you will
have some predefined activities
basically pre defined test case folders
predefined uh modules are the controls
okay that are already captured
okay and
here so once you land on here I'm going
to create a new reusable test block
because see emptying a shopping cart is
a reusable function so anytime multiple
test cases I can reuse that right so
that's why I'm going to use reusable
test step blocks okay okay so if you
remember in my previous um uh specialist
level one sessions right I explained you
how to create libraries and then how can
you create reusable test blocks right so
if you see this is my library I want to
create a new reusable test block here
okay right click create new reusable
test
block and name this as
empty shopping
cart okay so this is my new reusable
tester block let's concentrate empty
shopping cart now let us insert the
modules I want to insert the module
called top menu three times okay first
insert the top menu and name this as
navigate to shopping
Cod navigate to
shopping cart done let me insert One
More Time same top menu module and name
this
as log out and let me insert one more
time top
menu okay and this time name this as
wait until logged out log out wait
until logged
out logged
out okay and then now I want to insert a
standard module called close browser
right close
browser that's it now let us insert the
values okay first what we are going to
do you need to click on uh shopping cart
correct let's click on that means I need
to put some x value here and your action
mode as input and then I need to click
on log out so basically of course once
you go to the shopping cart you will be
performing removal of the emptying the
shopping C I'm going to tell you that
okay and log out once you log out you
need to wait until this login link
appears so for that here you need to
provide the
login visible visibility criteria if it
is visible right
visible is equal to
True wait until visible is true that
means I need to select the action mode
as wait on so I'm instructing
tasa wait until this login is visible
true okay until login visible true right
so once that is done once that is done
now I'm going to close the browser
correct so here title of the browser is
demo star I'm using regular expression
okay done
now here now I need to perform empty
once I go to the shopping cart I need to
perform empty right emptying the
shopping cart so for that let me
introduce a new test step
create while create while
statement okay what I'm going to do I'm
going to Let's collapse all these I need
to bring this while loop after navigate
to shopping cart after navigating to
shopping cart I want to perform some
actions what I need to empty the
shopping cart correct so now first let's
concentrate on condition under while
loop let's go to condition so here I
want to import a module called shopping
cart correct so I have to go to the
shopping cart under shopping
cart I need to verify if this shopping
cart has a shopping cart table if you
remember if you add any item that item
will be stored in the table table
correct let me add some items okay let's
log in and add some items so that you
understand very
well so go to oper and shoes add jeans
add something add bag right so now you
go to shopping cart I want to verify if
the table exist right this shopping card
table correct so for that I need to see
condition is if if if your shopping cart
products this is the table this is your
table if this exist that means go here
select
exist equal
to
True right but here action mode is
verify I want to verify if this table
exist or not if this exist then let's go
to to your Loop what it needs to do it
needs to start emptying the card correct
so contr
T
again shopping cart in import the same
module and here I need to select right
in the table this is my first row I have
to select first row checkbox for that go
to
rows and
then select this first
row dollar one so I've already explained
you about how to handle the tables web
tables in my previous sessions okay I
would recommend you guys to visit those
videos okay and here once you select one
you will see see remove this is my
remove column remove column right under
this remove
column again here my
um action mode should be again select
sorry not this one so this one this one
this one is
Select under remove column under remove
column there is a remove checkbox I need
to check this right so that's why I have
to change this to input
and this is Select this as
true this checkbox should be true
understand so this checkbox is
true select select select and then this
is true and once that is done so once I
select this I need to update the
shopping cart so for
that click on shopping cart update
shopping cart button correct once that
is done again it goes back to the
condition do you have a shopping cart
still Yes again come
here again now select the first
checkbox and then update the shopping
cart so as soon as you update the
shopping cart your shopping cart is
let's say select this update the
shopping cart done right now I have
another item so it goes back to the
condition still this table exist yes and
then it goes here and selects your first
selects your first checkbox and then
clicks on update shopping cart
correct so that's how we are going to
perform so once that is done I think we
are good now we are ready to run this
particular reusable test step block
correct so
let's okay for that first before you run
you need to make sure that you have some
let me add some more uh items to the
shopping cart okay let me add this also
to the shopping cart and then let me add
this also the shopping cart
okay um okay let me select this add to
the shopping cart okay so I have total
four items okay and
here yeah I have two bags okay right now
I need to run now okay you should be
loging and
then
let's oh you need not to click on you
it's going to click on shopping cart
anyway so let's go
here okay okay so now right click and
run in
scratchbook see clicked on shopping cart
now see it's checked first checkbox
updated shopping cart second updated
shopping cart now it's empty it's going
to log out and then it's going to close
the
browser right once this login link
identifies it will close the
browser done it closed the browser so
our test case is passed see everything
is passed while loop repeated how many
times see this while loop repeated four
times
because there are four items 1 2 3 4
that is the reason it repeated four
times and then logged out and waited
until the login appears and close the
browser okay so hope you all understand
the concept very well it is very very
important Concept in the real time okay
if you have any queries leave your
queries in the comment box I'll try to
respond to your queries thank
you
[Music]